foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
this is still the cultivation
listen to what we had last time
region
was not solution
it was not a malicious form of
distributions
we can even go farther and say
them
had no intention of transgression
actually
here in the Quran
in Surah 20
but what happened to Vietnam was that he
forgot
he was not strong enough
he forgot
he also learned
the Surah six
verse 68
Surah 12 verse 42
in Surah 18 verse 63
58 verse 19 so
that
creature that makes us forget the most
important things it is no less than
shaytan himself
makes us
forget
and thus we can conclude the basis of
this verses that I have generated
because shaytan who made
forget
I think there's not much speculation to
the point
however
the fact that Adam forgot
even temporarily
leads us to assume that he has forgotten
something that he knew you cannot forget
something that you never knew we never
know
and that we had some speculation last
time and I submitted to you brothers and
sisters
that
what is known for God
what what what what what Allah himself
told him
verse 31
is very clear
Allah
all the names
or commentary on this point
seven said
that these names which Allah taught Adam
has to do
with Allah himself
who Allah is
what Allah is
is power
more important that he is the source of
all power
and knowing these qualities Allah
in order by his names
Jesus is profound a deep form of
knowledge
it makes us understand
the
ayas around us and not only the signs
around us but the science of within us
Quran speaks of designs outside US
without him within
and if we know Allah's manifestations
without and with be enough
the high form of knowledge I'm insisting
we will be able to see all phenomena is
the true life
natural phenomena both physical and
biological anything ourselves
psychological phenomena and what is
cycle and what this psychological
phenomena brings about
individual and social phenomena
all of these things
our birth
of childhood our youth
our death
our love
our 20 hatreds
our resentment emotions regulations
all of these things even Warfare between
groups and so on all of these represent
manifestations of Allah's creative power
here is the ruler he rules everything
and nothing can happen without his will
then we thought also of Allah crazy
something of his spirit
into England it's very interesting on at
least three points Quran says that Allah
bring it into enough some things
means
from his spirit
but it's very important if you're not
saying he's low he's the spirit
because then
Allah will be creating Adam Allah which
is a preparation
something
what does this mean
when we have peace in Surah 15 verse 29
in Surah 32 verse 9
in Surah 38 verse 72.
and this is what I believe up to you
conflict what I'm saying
to accept or reject My Views or to use
My Views as a Point of Departure for you
to go deeper into it all times and
alternative interpretation
my interest is that
everything breathing into
Adam something of his spirit and a
spirit
first
the capacity
the capacity to know
to know
the name themselves
for it man does not have the capacity to
know the name he cannot know
this is very clear let's say a before
today
another word Allah has given him
the capacity or knowledge
then his face of knowledge knowledge to
know about Allah himself
Allah is so great
nothing cannot allow
and is that something who knows a lot
has something given to him I hope this
is very clear it is a philosophical
truth
you cannot know Allah unless Allah
himself has given you the power to know
him because he is so great and so above
her
no one less than Allah can know him but
Allah gave pan he's part of his breath a
deep breath of Allah is what allows us
to know Allah all right now this is a
very profound view I hope you will not
forget it
but more than that
it's not just a matter of giving man the
power knowing
Allah I believe has given us
to manifest
some of the qualities which we attribute
to him
the Quran is full of this attribute
when the Quran says that Allah this
destroys
we don't know we can destroy can we
destroyed
why we will be storing things day after
day
and so
we have no capacities
this I think is a second but just as
important meaning
oh
the bread of Allah
and it's not that we just have this
capacity
because the capacity is very many
there must be effective equalities in
the relations between Allah and Mankind
such that these qualities can become
what we would call actual
in other words
we may have
the capacity to feel pity or to love
but that capacity can only will always
remain a capacity unless there is
something that will actualize that
capacity into something that is real
so if we have the capacity for nursing
that capacity with remaining capacity it
can only be accurized
on account of certain order
all these Messengers can teach us how to
actualize this capacity
incidentally this point shows the
necessity of Revelation
so I think we've said so much about
these powers to know these Powers we
create these Powers destroyed
these powers to have fitted
into sympathize the ability to have what
you call this fine sense of
consideration
and again
if you say that this breath from Allah
in mankind
represents the most important part of
man's complex nature
foreign
but we also say based on the Quran that
he partakes of the breath for the spirit
of Allah
this spirit in mankind is the highest
part
the most excellent part of man's whole
or not
it cannot be otherwise so it comes from
Allah itself
it does not belong to us although we are
utilizing it
and now we can understand different some
of his verses the Quran
we need them in here say to Allah Allah
we have wronged ourselves we have ruled
ourselves what is the wrong
so
I'm superior
they realized that they had wrote the
most important part of themselves that
part which belongs to Allah and he's
trying to
find that part of Allah actually they
ended up hurting themselves because no
man can harm enough
so if you're angry and you insult Allah
you don't tell me enough you are hungry
yourself
so when you harm or being gay
this spirit that Allah had visited to us
in the long run you are harming or we
are harming ourselves
but it was the recognition of this
of this mistake
that made Adam depend and as we all know
is Allah is the old merciful any
response
to this repentance Allah Relentless
thoughts either gave words of Revelation
to him and more important for us now he
promised mankind revelation
or descending of a guidance
believe
mankind all of us are reminders
it was at this reminder by definition a
reminder is something to counter up and
forgetfulness because Man was created
with that if he was not created as a God
and therefore people
because necessary mechanisms
they are a sorrow descending of prophets
these are forms of reminder
they are what you call remain princess
Muhammad it's called a rename
Revelations are relatable reminder
the Quran is the perfect reminder
is a technique
not to forget which means the same as
saying that Salah prayer is a technique
to give on reminding us and you will
find it Surah 20 verse 14th and Surah 76
verses 25 26. look
shaytan as the source of forgetfulness
is an enemy
of prophets shaytan is an enemy of
Revelation shaytan is an enemy of the
Quran then shaytan is
the greatest enemy of Salah
one of his angels on Earth is precisely
to make man forget all of these things
done
but now
getting tired of talking about China
let's go back to
the bread of Allah
that's really the place of Allah and his
teaching of the name to Adam to the
purpose of man's creation
Quran says in Surah 6 verse 102. is
Surah 20 verse 14.
in Surah 51 verse 15. and so on
very clear
that Allah created man
to worship
or serve him
devoted
Arabic word the Earth is
to serve
this reveals immediately that creation
is purposes
and one of the meanings of heart when
Allah is called
is that he creates with a purpose
certainly he must in some way or another
revealed to man the nature of this
purpose either by putting in man's
nature a kind of primeval knowledge or
by revelation
for example
if you get you want to be the house
when you get a carpenter when you bring
it to the land we just tell him
what to do
what's going to be a big house a rooted
house
foreign
if that is the case which is the case it
is part of man's nature already to
recognize Allah but more than that Allah
gives us revelation
if it doesn't give us the knowledge
actually the propensity to accept such
knowledge when prophets appear
and thus again I submit to you all
that in giving Man part of his breath
and he is dealing in Hindi capacity or
potentialities to have to lie certain
qualities
very important
Allah makes it a beautiful man
to understand the names and to make such
potentialities operative or functional
in individual and social life now this
is very strong
statement that is
if God has given you the capacity to be
compassionate and if God has given us
the capacity to become patient elbow it
follows it is a duty for us to be
compassionate
I've been a very strong stance I don't
know what ethical philosophers say about
it
but if it's part of man's nature because
you have the breath of Allah in a life
compassionate When you pray this unto us
he gave us the capacity to be
compassionate therefore she used the
Quran to develop our capacity for
compassion and certainly for knowledge
Allah is the nowhere
any father has given us the power to
know it becomes our duty to know
therefore again
it is part of worship or part of service
to Allah
but more than that as I mentioned
earlier
it is part of
worship to develop those capacities
which Allah
but as we discussed
England
and Mankind for the matter
use such capacity in a manner showing
lack of restraint we forget
it brief Powers capacities can be
misused or abused
therefore
I'll give an example the capacity for
patients sometimes can be used as a
technique
for Revenge
combustion also
keep music
Ian people therefore it's not real
compassion
therefore it now becomes clear to all of
us why instructions must come from Allah
himself
regarding the use of such power the ends
of such power
this is one of the fundamental meaning
of Revelation
any man has no free will there will be
no problem if there is
this but no man has alternative by the
nature of his free will
that can stipend his potentiality or
actualize his potentialities towards
selfies or wrong end therefore
it is important for us to share
preparation and he or she who looks to
Allah as the source of revelation will
have other responding to such person
that Allah will give the Quran
the position of Allah's breath of Amen
it's a test
it is a test I have been repeating and
over repeating
on how we should
develop our potentialities
and have them directed properly
then and now has given us to documents
how to
actualize these potentiality and leave
it towards the destiny that yesterday
the more we develop our potentialities
for the good
that is the more we develop our
potentialities in accordance with the
last guidance
the more our spirit grows
which is the same as saying the more of
a last breath in our important all right
I think this is our world
pathology it's like saying a is equal to
a so one plus one is equal to two
the more we just developed our
potentialities which other gave us for
the good that is the more we are
listening or remembering Allah
the more is our spirit flowing this is
the spirit is the highest form of our
soul the Lord is our soul growth now we
started being emphasizing about the
growth of our thoughts I'm sure he has
his own performed meaning for what's
meant by our soul God I'm only giving
one meaning one possible meaning of what
it means to say that it's all growth to
me this all growth means that is iron
portion that can survive spirit
so to put it politically
the more of a life Spirit you have in
you the more of divine elements you have
in you
the more we remember Allah
and do what is Remembrance and things in
action
the more that it will grow right the
consumer of Allah spirit is enough
therefore the more spirituals we become
so to say it is now so and so is a
particular meaning it does not confuse
it with what other people
you know say about social speaker we see
that these transcendental uh political
people
say oh this is very speaker well I'm not
the one who's going to fight with these
people about the use of George Pizza
they have their own meaning what
spiritually
the Jews in the Christians I assume have
also the meaning of spirituality
but in terms of the Quran we have the
meaning
foreign
and what does it mean very clear you see
more we remember Allah understand his
name
understand the manifestation of this
nation without and without God
and therefore we can conclude easily the
verse we remember Allah the more our
soul will think the infinite of his
Spirit right
Allah
be more deep breath in our the disciples
we are not allowing him to have to learn
and not
we can now give a deeper meaning
to the world's righteousness for taqwa
it is this
start walking means righteousness can
mean to us now a consistent
investigating consciousness of Allah
there is the description of the growth
of the Soul
and it says that the growing soul is a
soul that knows the difference between
right and wrong the assumption is that
the person is following Iran the Surah
62 verse 2
the Quran speaks to the functions of
messenger
visitors comes to help men grow not grow
physically
spiritually
verse 159 Ibrahim prays to Allah he
prays to Allah to send messenger to
teach Muslims in spiritual and in wisdom
they have to fix man what man does not
know
verse 151
it's clearly shown that growth growth
means growth of the Soul
it means
knowledge of the scripture number one it
means gaining wisdom for acquiring
wisdom from such a knowledge of the
scripture an important coming to know
what man did not know before or what man
cannot know through his own effort it is
known as a king come only to the health
of Allah
and if we go to Surah 62 verses 2 to 4
in Surah 4 verse 113
here we know deeper the meaning of Allah
increase or bound that great for it
consists precisely in Hidden mankind
these three things
and you all know what it is
because it's integrates of this
precisely in teaching us scripture
allowing us to have wisdom from
following his spiritual in other words
we can say
one of the greatest Gifts of Allah is
precisely giving us the techniques to
counter up forgetfulness so that we do
not fall into
the crowd of poor ancestral data
now it also becomes easier for us to
understand what the Quran means when you
say that those who forget Allah forget
the soul that is
foreign they're very consistent those
who forget Allah forget their souls as I
told you earlier
you cannot know or not
unless Allah gives you the power to know
him Allah is so great no one nothing can
do Allah
himself put something in him or that
thing to know him he is the meaning of
knowledge
and he knows that the relation of
to know him
but those who insists in rejecting Allah
who in effect even if they say Allah
Allah Allah 20 000 times a day
if they don't mean it they forget the
soul
why oh because we've met you so many
times is the most important part of man
it is the part in man which represents
part of Allah Spirits in him therefore
to say that Mr X forgets Allah he's the
same as saying that Mr X forgets his
soul this is again another tautology
it's like saying a is
true in Surah 20 124 says that he who
forgets Allah will be blind in the last
day
that those who forget Allah's revelation
will be forgotten by Allah in the last
day same thing in Surah 45 verse 34 all
this means that such individuals will be
lost
in the last day it also means that the
stones have sunk
and for all practical purposes disappear
there are just pure place
don't come in that the most essential
part
some other forms of play
in poor Adam
he forgot
but alhamdulillah
he was able to remember again
he was fast
I suppose so good for him and for his
descendant for when he found out he was
abandoned by shaytan he immediately
turned the parent plan to Allah
and Allah if
mankind the instruments to counter up
forgetfulness this is up to us well I
don't know really how fast
is that repented maybe I've been a
influence of stars when he says
foreign
or 17th
that a man can do in a hurry
up says take it easy in everything don't
hurry except in around six or seven
things I don't remember the six or seven
things but I read it many years ago
but I just want to remember the Arab
said
go is no except
when you commit a scene immediately as
repentance from Allah but you can see
this is Quran
number two
when your guests come to your house and
they're hungry immediately feed them
don't take it easy this is our these
Arab hospitality
the third one is
if you watch person's money please pay
your debts this is common sense
before the sun feels dissolved
when a man dies hurry up with his burial
before his things
and one of them I think the last one I
forgot is
to go back to the football
here we can see that the Fatiha really
summarizes very well everything that we
have said
that Allah is the lord of the world
but the master of the day of judgment
we need his help and guidance
and we pray to him for it in other words
we assume we accept from him that need
his help and therefore we want his
revelation
and we pray to him that we should not be
among these Believers and deeper faith
they have forgotten Allah even if they
say Allah Allah Allah
in Believers and hypocrites for all
practical purposes
are saying
with their mouth what their heart denied
they do not fear Him they didn't appear
Allah they do not accept him as Lord
they do not accept him
a judge
and we pray to Allah
that he helped us remember him
and this very beautiful person Quran I
don't know what's the number
Allah says remember me and I'll remember
you be thankful unto me
and do not belong to those who deny the
disease delivered
Allah
foreign
[Music]
or something
else
um
here
thank you
um